Typography gives character to text.
排版样式给文字提供了特殊效果
If you think about all the web pages you have visited,
回想一下所有你浏览过的 web 页面
all the texts you have seen,
所有你见过的文字
all of that has been designed and styled in different ways,
它们都被不同的方式设计和装饰过
the totality of which is what we call typography.
所有的一切都可以叫做排版样式
CSS provides many meaningful ways to style your text through different properties.
CSS 通过不同的属性提供了很多方式来装饰你的文本
Let's see a few of them in action and then we'll go into more detail so
让我们先来看一些实际例子 然后我们再具体深入的了解一下
that you can learn all the tools you have to bring your text to life,
最后你会掌握所有排版样式相关的工具 让文字“活”过来
because that's what CSS provides.
这就是使用 CSS 的最终目的
So some things we'll go over in the demo are,
所以我们要了解的内容有
text-align, font-size, color, and line-height.
text-align、font-size、color 和 line-height
But these are just four of many examples that come together in
它们只是你的创意工具箱众多例子中的一部分
a creative toolkit to make your own customized and gorgeous text. Let's check it out.
可以实现自定义精美的文字内容 让我们来看一看吧
Here, you can see I have a document set up with just one div,
这里你可以看到有一个简单的文件 仅有一个 div 元素
which is a simple div called typography that has some text in it.
它有个 typography 的 id 属性和一些文字内容
Right now if you go look at the web-page,
不过如果我们在浏览器里面看看的话
you'll see it's small and a little hard to read and
你可以看见文字有一点点小 不太容易阅读
there's a number of reasons that this text doesn't really stand out.
为了让它变得更出众 我们有很多可以改进的地方
So let's try to give it some life, shall we?
让我们来做一些有趣的事情
One thing we can do is we can align our text center,
首先 我们可以把文本内容居中显示
we can give it a color to stand out a little bit more.
然后给它一个更明显的颜色
Actually, how about yellow.
比如 黄色
So now you can see we have centered yellow text.
现在我们可以看到一堆居中的黄色文本
For me, I'm a little bit of a typography nut and
对于我来说 我对排版样式要求通常比较高
I think there is a optimal width that you should have.
所以我认为有一些理想的宽度会更好一些
This is too long a line.
这一行太长了
People can't read text that long.
用户没办法一次性阅读太长的文字
So I like to set a width of around 64 percent.
所以我们设置一个百分之 64 的宽度
Now it's starting to become a little more readable.
现在它的可读性应该好多了
Margin auto puts it back in the center.
再设置外边距为 auto 来让它居中显示
So now we can see we've aligned our text,
现在我们已经居中了文字
we've given it a color and a width,
增加了一些宽度和颜色
but it's still a little small.
但是文字尺寸有一点小
So the font-size property will let us set.
我们可以使用 font-size 属性来设置它
Either, we could do 24 pixels but another thing we'll go into in later lessons is the em.
我们可以设置为 24 像素 另外一种可以使用的单位是 em 我们会在以后了解到它
So 1.1 em font size is a relative font size to the body font size of 18 points.
1.1 em 这里会相对于 body 的字体尺寸计算 也就是相对于 18pt
So 1.1 will be just a little bit bigger.
所以 1.1 会稍微大一点点
We might want to go way bigger and say 1.4.
我们设置为 1.4 来让它更大一些
Now, the lines are starting to come together a bit,
现在 每行之间的距离还是有一些紧密
and there's actually a CSS property called line-height which will
CSS 中的 line-height (行高) 属性可以帮助我们
let us change the distance in between the lines of text.
改变行与行之间的距离
So let's do something bizarre just so you can get a look.
我们先设置夸张点 这样你好看清楚区别
If we set it to 3.3 em,
比如设置为 3.3 em
then you see we can have these big bold lines in between.
你可以看到它们之间就有很大的行距
Font-size, line-height, margin, width, color, text-align,
你可以灵活搭配使用
these are just some of the properties that come together to
Font-size、line-height、margin、width、color、text-align 用好这些属性
allow you create a typography with CSS.
来创造出你想要的 CSS 排版样式